{"test_questions": [[{"question": "You can add a row using SQL in a database with which of the following?", "opta": "ADD", "optb": "CREATE", "optc": "INSERT", "optd": "MAKE", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The command to remove rows from a table 'CUSTOMER' is:", "opta": "REMOVE FROM CUSTOMER ...", "optb": "DROP FROM CUSTOMER ...", "optc": "DELETE FROM CUSTOMER WHERE ...", "optd": "UPDATE FROM CUSTOMER ...", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SQL WHERE clause:", "opta": "limits the column data that are returned.", "optb": "limits the row data are returned.", "optc": "Both A and B are correct.", "optd": "Neither A nor B are correct.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the original purpose of SQL?", "opta": "To specify the syntax and semantics of SQL data definition language", "optb": "To specify the syntax and semantics of SQL manipulation language", "optc": "To define the data structures", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wildcard in a WHERE clause is useful when?", "opta": "An exact match is necessary in a SELECT statement.", "optb": "An exact match is not possible in a SELECT statement.", "optc": "An exact match is necessary in a CREATE statement.", "optd": "An exact match is not possible in a CREATE statement.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A view is which of the following?", "opta": "A virtual table that can be accessed via SQL commands", "optb": "A virtual table that cannot be accessed via SQL commands", "optc": "A base table that can be accessed via SQL commands", "optd": "A base table that cannot be accessed via SQL commands", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The command to eliminate a table from a database is:", "opta": "REMOVE TABLE CUSTOMER;", "optb": "DROP TABLE CUSTOMER;", "optc": "DELETE TABLE CUSTOMER;", "optd": "UPDATE TABLE CUSTOMER;", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ON UPDATE CASCADE ensures which of the following?", "opta": "Normalization", "optb": "Data Integrity", "optc": "Materialized Views", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SQL data definition commands make up a(n) ________ .", "opta": "DDL", "optb": "DML", "optc": "HTML", "optd": "XML", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is valid SQL for an Index?", "opta": "CREATE INDEX ID;", "optb": "CHANGE INDEX ID;", "optc": "ADD INDEX ID;", "optd": "REMOVE INDEX ID;", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SQL keyword(s) ________ is used with wildcards.", "opta": "LIKE only", "optb": "IN only", "optc": "NOT IN only", "optd": "IN and NOT IN", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the correct order of keywords for SQL SELECT statements?", "opta": "SELECT, FROM, WHERE", "optb": "FROM, WHERE, SELECT", "optc": "WHERE, FROM,SELECT", "optd": "SELECT,WHERE,FROM", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A subquery in an SQL SELECT statement is enclosed in:", "opta": "braces -- {...}.", "optb": "CAPITAL LETTERS.", "optc": "parenthesis -- (...) .", "optd": "brackets -- [...].", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The result of a SQL SELECT statement is a(n) ________ .", "opta": "report", "optb": "form", "optc": "file", "optd": "table", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are the five built-in functions provided by SQL?", "opta": "COUNT, SUM, AVG, MAX, MIN", "optb": "SUM, AVG, MIN, MAX, MULT", "optc": "SUM, AVG, MULT, DIV, MIN", "optd": "SUM, AVG, MIN, MAX, NAME", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an SQL SELECT statement querying a single table, according to the SQL-92 standard the asterisk (*) means that:", "opta": "all columns of the table are to be returned.", "optb": "all records meeting the full criteria are to be returned.", "optc": "all records with even partial criteria met are to be returned.", "optd": "None of the above is correct.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The HAVING clause does which of the following?", "opta": "Acts like a WHERE clause but is used for groups rather than rows.", "optb": "Acts like a WHERE clause but is used for rows rather than columns.", "optc": "Acts like a WHERE clause but is used for columns rather than groups.", "optd": "Acts EXACTLY like a WHERE clause.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SQL -92 wildcards are ____ and ____ .", "opta": "asterisk (*); percent sign (%)", "optb": "percent sign (%); underscore (_)", "optc": "underscore(_); question mark (?)", "optd": "question mark (?); asterisk (*)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To remove duplicate rows from the results of an SQL SELECT statement, the ________ qualifier specified must be included.", "opta": "ONLY", "optb": "UNIQUE", "optc": "DISTINCT", "optd": "SINGLE", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The benefits of a standard relational language include which of the following?", "opta": "Reduced training costs", "optb": "Increased dependence on a single vendor", "optc": "Applications are not needed.", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following do you need to consider when you make a table in SQL?", "opta": "Data types", "optb": "Primary keys", "optc": "Default values", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SQL query and modification commands make up a(n) ________ .", "opta": "DDL", "optb": "DML", "optc": "HTML", "optd": "XML", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When three or more AND and OR conditions are combined, it is easier to use the SQL keyword(s):", "opta": "LIKE only.", "optb": "IN only.", "optc": "NOT IN only.", "optd": "Both IN and NOT IN.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Microsoft Access wildcards are ____ and ____ .", "opta": "asterisk (*); percent sign (%)", "optb": "percent sign (%); underscore (_)", "optc": "underscore(_); question mark (?)", "optd": "question mark (?); asterisk (*)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find the SQL statement below that is equal to the following: SELECT NAME FROM CUSTOMER WHERE STATE = 'VA';", "opta": "SELECT NAME IN CUSTOMER WHERE STATE IN ('VA');", "optb": "SELECT NAME IN CUSTOMER WHERE STATE = 'VA';", "optc": "SELECT NAME IN CUSTOMER WHERE STATE = 'V';", "optd": "SELECT NAME FROM CUSTOMER WHERE STATE IN ('VA');", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following sorts rows in SQL?", "opta": "SORT BY", "optb": "ALIGN BY", "optc": "ORDER BY", "optd": "GROUP BY", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To sort the results of a query use:", "opta": "SORT BY.", "optb": "GROUP BY.", "optc": "ORDER BY.", "optd": "None of the above is correct.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To define what columns should be displayed in an SQL SELECT statement:", "opta": "use FROM to name the source table(s) and list the columns to be shown after SELECT.", "optb": "use USING to name the source table(s) and list the columns to be shown after SELECT.", "optc": "use SELECT to name the source table(s) and list the columns to be shown after USING.", "optd": "use USING to name the source table(s) and list the columns to be shown after WHERE.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SQL can be used to:", "opta": "create database structures only.", "optb": "query database data only.", "optc": "modify database data only.", "optd": "All of the above can be done by SQL.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SQL statement that queries or reads data from a table is ________ .", "opta": "SELECT", "optb": "READ", "optc": "QUERY", "optd": "None of the above is correct.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SQL keyword BETWEEN is used:", "opta": "for ranges.", "optb": "to limit the columns displayed.", "optc": "as a wildcard.", "optd": "None of the above is correct.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A subquery in an SQL SELECT statement:", "opta": "can only be used with two tables.", "optb": "can always be duplicated by a join.", "optc": "has a distinct form that cannot be duplicated by a join.", "optd": "cannot have its results sorted using ORDER BY.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "________ was adopted as a national standard by ANSI in 1992.", "opta": "Oracle", "optb": "SQL", "optc": "Microsoft Access", "optd": "DBase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SQL is:", "opta": "a programming language.", "optb": "an operating system.", "optc": "a data sublanguage.", "optd": "a DBMS.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}